{
    "id": "d2a39a298e374d31b74ba32b2c3d6a1f",
    "title": "Clauses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The jury believed that the man was guilty.",
            "description": "Here the clause ‘that the man was guilty’ is the object of the verb believed. Noun clauses act as the subject or object of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "Adjective clause",
                "Noun clause",
                "Adverb clause"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Come when you like.",
            "description": "Here the clause ‘when you like’ modifies the noun come.",
            "answers": [
                "Noun clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Adverb clause"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I know the girl who won the prize.",
            "description": "Here the clause ‘who won the prize’ modifies the noun girl. Adjective clauses give additional information about a noun or pronoun in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "Noun clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Adverb clause"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He confessed that he was guilty.",
            "description": "Here the clause ‘that he was guilty’ is the object of the verb confessed.",
            "answers": [
                "Noun clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Adverb clause"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I know you have great regard for him.",
            "description": "Here the clause ‘you have great regard for him’ is the object of the verb know. ",
            "answers": [
                "Noun clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Adverb clause"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Do you think that I am a fool?",
            "description": "Here the clause ‘that I am a fool’ is the object of the verb think.",
            "answers": [
                "Noun clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Adverb clause"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Before I die I want to see Venice.",
            "description": "Here the clause ‘before I die’ gives the time of the action mentioned in the main clause. Hence it is an adverb clause of time.",
            "answers": [
                "Noun clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Adverb clause"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The hand that rocks the cradle rules the world.",
            "description": "Here the clause ‘that rocks the cradle’ modifies the noun hand. ",
            "answers": [
                "Noun clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Adverb clause"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I know a boy whose father serves in the army.",
            "description": "Here the clause ‘whose father serves in the army’ modifies the noun boy. ",
            "answers": [
                "Noun clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Adverb clause"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I will not go until he arrives.",
            "description": "Here the clause ‘until he arrives’ gives the time of the action mentioned in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "Noun clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Adverb clause"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The coffee maker that I bought for my wife is expensive.",
            "description": "Here the clause that I bought for my wife modifies the noun coffee maker.",
            "answers": [
                "Noun clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Adverb clause"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If you give respect, you get respect.",
            "description": "Here the clause 'if you give respect' expresses a condition. Hence it is an adverb clause of condition. ",
            "answers": [
                "Noun clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Adverb clause"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}